Edward D. Tuttle papers, 1862-1928
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Edward D. Tuttle papers, 1862-1928
AZ 514
Personal correspondence, drafts of articles, photocopies of published articles, and various reminiscences relating to Arizona history and Army experiences including the Apache campaigns.
Tuttle, Edward D., 1834-1928
.8 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Arizona pioneer; Army officer, 4th California Infantry, 1862-1865; and author of articles on Arizona history.
Scope and Content Note
Personal correspondence, drafts of articles, photocopies of published articles, and various reminiscences relating to Arizona history and Army experiences including the Apache campaigns. Correspondence includes letters to his sister during his Army service, 1862-1865.
Access Terms
Colorado Steam Navigation Company
Arizona -- History -- Sources
Graham County (Ariz.) -- History -- Sources
Yuma (Ariz.) -- History -- Sources
Arizona -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Sources
Correspondence
Container List
- Correspondence while in California and Arizona. October 1862-November 1866 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence while at Fort Yuma. December 1866-Semptember 1868 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence while at Camp Willow Grove, Camp Mohave, Gila Bend, and Fort Yuma. October 1868-January 1869 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence while an employee of the Colorado Steam Navigation Company. March 1869-May 1870 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence while a resident of California. 1870-1876 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous correspondence. 1880-1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Photocopies of correspondence to and from Tuttle concerning Arizona history. 1922-1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Photocopies of manuscript drafts of articles by Tuttle on Arizona history (primarily about Graham, Mohave, Yavapai, and Yuma Counties); his experiences as an officer in the 4th California Infantry, and the Apache campaigns. 1862-1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photocopies of correspondence to his sister. 1862-1865 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Photocopies of newspaper articles on Arizona history. 1922 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Photocopies of an article by Tuttle: Article on the Pueblo Viejo Valley which appeared in The Arizonan, Volume 1, Numbers 49-50. January 19, 1899-February 1899 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Photocopies of an article by Tuttle: Article entitled The River Colorado in Arizona Historical Review, pages 50-68. July 1928 (Box 2, Folder 5)